A Guide to the Richmond (Va.) Office of the City Engineer, Records, 1809-1975
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Richmond (Va.) Office of the City Engineer, Records, 1809-1975
Library of Virginia
34886a-b
Accession 34886a (Barcode number 1205723) consists of 1400 sheets, mostly India ink on linen with some blueprints and Diazo prints (61 x 91 cm. or smaller). Accession 34886b (Barcode numbers 1156595-1159596) contains 2 volumes(119 p. and 102 p.) of primarily pricking, pencil, pen and ink, and watercolor washes on paper (48 x 33 cm. and 50 x 38 cm.)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to architectural and engineering plans and drawings of current governmental buildings requires a written request from the prospective user and written authorization from the appropriate authority within the agency occupying the facility.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the City of Richmond (Va.), Department of Public Works, Surveys Division, Richmond, Virginia, 12 May 1995.
Biographical/Historical Information
The functions of the office of the City Engineer for the City of Richmond had their origins in the work of William Mayo (d. 1744), who drew the original plat of Richmond ca. 1735. In 1780 an official "Surveyor of the City" was appointed. In 1866 the office was abolished and its duties were consolidated with those of the office of the City Engineer, which had been created in 1853. The title was changed to Department of Public Works in 1919.
Scope and Content
This accession consists of two series: Architectural drawings and plans (Accession 34886a) and Plats (Accession 34886b).
Series I: Architectural drawings and plans is primarily the surviving papers of the office of the City Engineer during the administration of Wilfred Emory Cutshaw (1838-1907), Richmond City Engineer from 1873 to 1907. In the course of long storage at Richmond City Hall, other, later material was added to the Cutshaw-era files. This collection documents the important period of expansion in post-Reconstruction Richmond, a period that saw an increasing number of municipal projects. Among these were the establishment of the city water works and reservoir, numerous city parks, bridges, armories, schools, and the construction of a new City Hall. The collection also documents the expansion of the boundaries of the city, the annexation of Manchester, and the constant efforts of flood control in Shockoe Valley.
This series also contains nineteenth century maps of Richmond drawn by City Surveyors Richard Young (d. 1832) and Micajah Bates (1797-1861). Also included is a partial set of presentation plans for the 1883- 1894 Richmond City Hall by Elijah E. Myers (1832-1909), designs by Ruben Shirreffs (d. 1904) for Navy Hill (1893) and Nicholson Street (1893) schools, and, the most important document in the collection, the plan of the 1816-1818 Richmond City Hall by Robert Mills (1781-1855). This is the only surviving image of this structure from Mills' hand.
Series II: Plats consists of City of Richmond Plat Book A, 1826-1866, and Plat Book B, 1815-1862, denoting plats of various parts and properties of the city. These often include text that explains the particular surveys and give legal references or citations. These plats are unusual in that they have been elaborately shaded with watercolors. They are generally the work of Richard Young, City Surveyor from 1828 to 1832; Micajah Bates, City Surveyor from 1832 to 1861; and Thomas M. Ladd (1800-1866), City Surveyor and Superintendent of Streets from 1851 to 1866. The two plat books are partially indexed.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in the following series: Series I: Architectural drawings and plans, 1809-1975 and Series II: Plats, 1815-1866.
Contents List
- Series I. Architectural drawings and plans, 1809-1975.
  This series is organized according to project type: Armories, Bridges, Canals, Cemeteries, Electrical Service, Fire Department, Gas Works, Jails, Maps, Non-city Items, Miscellanious Material, Parks, Plats, Police Department, Ports, Railroads, Richmond City Hall, River and Creeks, Schools, Sewer and Drainage, Streets, Streetcars, and Tunnels.
  - Armory - Drilling Shed for / First Reg. Cavalry / Richmond, 5-B-1, [1893], Dimensions: 20 x 34 cm.-3/4 in. - 51 x 88 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 02)
    Drawn By: C. Whiteley Jr.
  - Armory - Drilling Shed for / First Reg. Cavalry / Richmond / Details of Iron Required, 5-B-1, 1893, Dimensions: 20 x 34 cm.-3/4 in. - 51 x 88 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 05)
    Drawn By: C. Whiteley Jr. Sep 5/93
  - Armory - Drilling Shed for / First Reg. Cavalry / Richmond, Va., 4-B-1, 1893, Dimensions: 20 x 35 in. - 51 x 89 in.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 02)
    Drawn By: C. Whiteley Jr. Sept 5/93
  - Armory - [Richmond] Howitzer Armory, 24-B-1 to 35-B-1, 1894, Dimensions: 23.5 x 33 in.; Scale: 1/4in = 1 ft.; Media: Pencil, India ink, and brown, red, and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 12 (Folder 04)
    Drawn By: W. E. Cutshaw, City Engineer (Sheet 7), Henry E. Baskervill, del. April '94 (Sheet 1)
  - Armory - [First Virginia Volunteers Battalion Armory] (Known as the Leigh Street Armory, home of African American militia company), 12-B-1to 21-B-1, 1895, Dimensions: 23-1/2 x 24 in. - 60 x 61 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on linen; Sheets: 10 (Folder 01)
    Drawn By: [Office of Richmond City Engineer]; CD # 61.
  - Armory - Plan / for / Reinforcing Regimental Armory Roof, 37-B-1, 1897, Dimensions: 10 x 32-1/4 in. - 25 x 82 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 05)
    Drawn By: City Engineer's Office / Richmond, Va.
  - Armory - Plan of Proposed Retaining Wall Bet. 7th. & 8th. Sts., 42-A-1, 1906, Dimensions: 15-1/4 x 33-3/4 in. - 40 x 86 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 04)
  - Armory - Market and Armory Building for the City of Richmond, Sixth and Marshall Streets, Richmond, VA, Y-10315, 1908, Dimensions: 91 x 132 cm. and smaller; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints (mended); Sheets: 15 (Folder Roll 1)
    Drawn By: Averill and Hall, Architects, 719 Union Trust Building, Washington, DC
  - Armory - City of Richmond, Va. / Plan of Site of Richmond / Light Infantry Blues Armory and / Second Market, 16-D-1, 1908, Dimensions: 22-1/4 x 30 in. - 56 x 76 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder 03)
  - Armory - [Plan showing existing properties and structures on site of Blues Armory], 16-D-1, 1908, Dimensions: 12-1/4 x 15 in. - 31 x 38 cm.; Scale: 1" = 30'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 03)
    Drawn By: [Office of Richmond City Engineer]
  - Armory - Swimming Pool for / Howitzer Armory / Richmond, Virginia, Y-11917, 1908, Dimensions: 25-1/2 x 29-1/2 in. - 65 x 75 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints (damaged); Sheets: 12 (Folder Roll 2)
    Drawn By: W. Leigh Carneal / Architect / J. A. Johnston M. E. / Richmond, Va.
  - Armory - Market & Armory Building / for / City of Richmond, Va., [No file number], 1909, Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints (very poor condition); Sheets: 30 (Folder Roll 5)
    Drawn By: Carneal & Johnston and American Bridge Company
  - Armory - First Virginia Regiment Armory / for / City of Richmond / Seventh and Marshall Sts. / Richmond, Virginia, [No file number], 1912, Dimensions: 23-1/4 x 34-1/2 in. - 59 x 88 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints (poor condition); Sheets: 10 (Folder Roll 12)
    Drawn By: Carneal & Johnston / Architects & Engineers / Richmond, Virginia
  - Armory - Alteration and Addition to the Howitzer Armory, [No file number], 1915, Dimensions: 86 x 116 cm. and smaller; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: Blueprints (mended); Sheets: 14 (Folder Roll 2)
    Drawn By: Carneal and Johnston, Architects and Engineers, Richmond, Virginia
  - Armory - Alterations and Additions to Heating System, Howitzers Armory, Richmond, Virginia, Y-10313, 1938, Dimensions: 69 x 51 1/2 cm.; Scale: 1/16" = 1'; Media: Blueprints (mended); Sheets: 5 (Folder Roll 1)
    Drawn By: Carneal, Johnston & Wright, Architects and Engineers, Richmond, Virginia
  - Armory - [First Regimental (Richmond Grays) Armory], 1-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 28 x 17-1/2 in. - 71 x 44 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink and colored inks on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 05)
    Drawn By: Unsigned
  - Armory - Lockers for Howitzer Armory, 22-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 15-1/4 x 12 in. - 39 x 30 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 04)
  - Armory - Armory / for / First Regiment Cavalry / Virginia Volunteers, 36-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 23-1/2 x 30 in. - 60 x 76 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on linen; Sheets: 6 (Folder 05)
    Drawn By: Edgerton S. Rogers / Walter R. Higham / Architects
  - Armory - Regimental Armory Roof Truss, 37-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 20-1/2 x 36 in. - 52 x 91 cm.; Scale: 1/8" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 05)
  - Armory - East Roof Truss, Regimental Armory, 37-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 20-1/2 x 36 in. - 52 x 91 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 05)
  - Armory - Drilling Shed for / First Reg. Cavalry / Richmond, 7-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 20 x 34 cm.-3/4 in. - 51 x 88 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 02)
  - Armory - Howitzer Drill Shed / Revised Plan / Truss No. 1 / Next to Howitzer Armory, 9-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 14-1/2 x 32-1/4 in. - 37 x 82 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 04)
  - Armory - Howitzer Drill Shed / Revised Plan / Truss No. 11 / Next to Cavalry Armory, 8-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 17-1/4 x 33-1/2 in. - 44 x 85 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 04)
  - Armory - Howitzer Drill Shed / Revised Plan / Trusses No. 2 to No. 10, 11-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 16-1/2 x 31-1/4 in. - 42 x 79 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 04)
    Drawn By: No signature given.
  - Armory - Howitzer Drill Shed / Revised Plan / Details of Iron Required, 10-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 16-1/2 x 26-1/4 in. - 42 x 67 cm.; Scale: 1" 1'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 04)
  - Armory - Medallion for / Armory Building. / Full Size / Make Two., 23-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 36-3/4 x 40-3/4 in. - 93 x 104 cm.; Scale: Full size; Media: Pencil, India ink, and brown ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 04)
  - Armory - Lockers for / Cavalry Armory 7th St., 36-B-1, n.d., Dimensions: 16-1/2 x 18 in. - 42 x 46 cm.; Scale: 1-1/2" = 1'; Media: 1pencil, India ink, and colored inks on linen, 1 pencil on heavy paper with cloth backing; Sheets: 2 (Folder 02)
  - Bridge - Richmond & Manchester Free Bridge / Diagrams to Accompany report of Reubin Shirreffs / May 15th 1888, 3-A-5, 1888, Dimensions: 32 x 16 in. - 81 x 41 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink on linen (damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 10)
  - Bridge - 'The Free Bridge' / Richmond to Manchester, Va. / Design for New Spans, Y-8384, 1889, Dimensions: 31-1/4 x 38 in. - 79 x 97 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: Contract for five spans awarded to / Edgemoor Bridge Works Oct. 28, 1889 / Rueben Shirriffs / Engineer
  - Bridge - 'The Free Bridge' / A Highway Deck Bridge / between / Richmond & Manchester Va., [No file number], 1889, Dimensions: 27-1/2 x 36-1/2 in. - 70 x 93 cm.; Scale: 1-1/2" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 7 (Folder 12)
    Drawn By: Built by / Edge Moor Bridge Works / Edge Moor, Del.
  - Bridge - James River Bridge / Richmond to Manchester, Va. / Present Trusses, 49-A-5, 1889, Dimensions: 22 x 34-1/2 in. - 56 x 88 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint (heavily damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 10)
  - Bridge - Designs for Remodeling / Free Bridge Va. / Richmond and Manchester, 17-B-4, 189, Dimensions: 16 x 38 in. - 41 x 96 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: Submitted by / Edge Moor Bridge Works / Edge Moor, Del. / Drawing No. 9872
  - Bridge - Plan of / Free Bridge / at / Richmond, Virginia / Showing Changes for Crossing / of / Chesapeake & Ohio R'y Co's Viaduct, 10758-B-2, 1895, Dimensions: 19-1/4 x 52 in. - 49 x 132 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint (heavily damaged and stained); Sheets: 1 (Folder 10)
    Drawn By: Office of 2nd Vice President / C & O R'y Co. Richmond, Va.
  - Bridge - Viaduct on Broad St. / from 12th. To 22nd. St. / for the / City of Richmond, Va., 14-B-4, 1895, Dimensions: 24 x 45-1/2 in. - 61 x 116 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: Submitted by the N.J. Steel & Iron Co. / Trenton, N. J.
  - Bridge - Suggestions for Raising and Altering / Free Bridge between Richmond & Manchester, Va. / W. E. Cutshaw, City Engineer, Richmond, Va., 17-B-4, 1896, Dimensions: 24-1/2 x 38 in. - 62 x 96 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink, red ink, and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: Submitted by the N. J. Steel & Iron Co. / Trenton, N. J.
  - Bridge - Map / of / Free Bridge / between / Richmond & Manchester, Va., 17-B-4, 1898, Dimensions: 33-1/2 x41-1/2 in. - 85 x 105 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen graph paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 08)
  - Bridge - Reconstruction of Free Bridge / To Clear C. & O. Viaduct / R. V. & T. Structure - C. & O. Ry., 61-C-1, 1900, Dimensions: 24 x 36 in. - 61 x 91 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 20 (Folder 09)
    Drawn By: Pencoyd Iron Works / Bridge and Constn. Dept. / Pencoyd, Pa.
  - Bridge - Proposed Bridge on Lombardy Street, 27-A-1, 1901, Dimensions: 5-3/4 x 13 in. - 14 x 33 cm.; Scale: 1" = 4'; Media: Pencil, India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: City Engineer's Office
  - Bridge - Proposed Bridge on Lombardy Street, 27-A-1b, 1901, Dimensions: 8-14 x 11 in. - 21 x 28 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
  - Bridge - Proposed Highway Bridge on Lombardy Street / Richmond, Va. / Over the Main Line of The Seaboard Air Line Ry., 27-A-1c, 1901, Dimensions: 14 x 35-1/4 in. - 36 x 89 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
    Drawn By: Portsmouth Va. July 27th 1901
  - Bridge - Proposed Bridge on Lombardy St. / Richmond, Va., 27-A-4, 1901, Dimensions: 15-3/4 x 35-3/4 in. - 40 x 91 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
  - Bridge - Plan of Bridge Over / Shockoe Creek at Dock St., 41-A-2, 1902, Dimensions: 17 x 28-3/4 in. - 43 x 73 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
  - Bridge - Sketch of Column Under Bridge of the / American Tobacco Co. over 25th St., 35-A-2, 1902, Dimensions: 19-3/4 x 14-3/4 in. - 50 x 38 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
  - Bridge - Proposed Highway Bridge on Lombardy Street / Richmond, Va. / Over the Main Line of The Seaboard Air Line Ry., 27-A-1, 1902, Dimensions:; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints (damaged); Sheets: 7 (Folder 07)
    Drawn By: Submitted by The Virginia Bridge & Iron Co., Roanoke, Virginia
  - Bridge - Calculations of Strains / on / 8 original spans of 'Free Bridge', [No file number], 1905, Dimensions: 23-1/4 x 36 in. - 59 x 91 cm.; Scale: None; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 10)
    Drawn By: F. B. Issacs / Engineer
  - Bridge - Plan for Highway Bridge Across Shockoe Creek at 14th and Leigh Streets (Location to be Determined Hereafter), 49-B-1, 1906, Dimensions: 21 x 24-1/2 in. - 53 x 62 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 06)
    Drawn By: City Engineer's Office / Richmond - Va.
  - Bridge - Plan for / Proposed Bridge over Bacon Quarter Branch at Oak St., 18-D-1, 1907, Dimensions: 30-1/4 x 50 in. - 77 x 124 cm.; Scale: 1" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: City Eng'r's Office / Richmond, Va. / C. L. Todd Jr. A. C E.
  - Bridge - Proposed Viaduct / for / City of Richmond, Va., 46-B-4, 1907, Dimensions: 24 x 35-1/2 in. - 61 x 90 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: Submitted by McClintic - Marshall Const. Co. / Pottstown, Pa.
  - Bridge - Sketch Showing Requirements of The City Engineer / for Southern Ry. Crossing of Shockoe Creek on Cary Street Richmond Va, 50-B-1, 1907, Dimensions: 20-1/4 x 28-1/4 in. -51 x 72 cm.; Scale: 1" = 4'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 06)
    Drawn By: City Eng'r's Office / Richmond Va / Fontaine Jones / Asst Engr / Delineator
  - Bridge - Plan and Elevation of Tredegar Iron Works and R.F. & P. Railroad Connection Trestle / Crossing Seventh St. South of Bragg St., 46-B-1, 1907, Dimensions: 17-1/4 x 25 in. - 44 x 64 cm.; Scale: 1" = 0'; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 06)
    Drawn By: City Engr's Office / Richmond, Va.
  - Bridge - Plan and Elevation of R.F.& P.Railroad Connection Trestle / Crossing Seventh St. South of Byrd St. / Showing position of bents in Streets, 47-B-1, 1907, Dimensions: 20 x 23-1/2 in. - 51 x 60 cm.; Scale: 1" = 10'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 06)
    Drawn By: City Engineer's Office, Richmond, VA
  - Bridge - City of Richmond, Va. / Viaduct on Lombardy St. / from Broad St. to Leigh St., 46-B-4, 1907, Dimensions: 24 x 36 in. - 61 x 91 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 2 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: Riverside Bridge Co. / Wheeling, W. Va.
  - Bridge - Lombardy Street Viaduct / City of Richmond, Va., 46-B-4, 1908, Dimensions: 12 x 17-3/4 in. - 30 x 45 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 3 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: Submitted by / Virginia Bridge & Iron Co. / Roanoke, Va.
  - Bridge - One Span of Free Bridge / showing / Trestle Bent & Floor Beam Supports / 8 spans like this, 17-D-19, 1908, Dimensions: 20-1/4 x 35-1/2 in. - 51 x 90 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 10)
    Drawn By: F. B. Isaac / Engineer
  - Bridge - City of Richmond Va. / Plan of Marshall St. / from / College St. to 21st. St. and Jefferson Ave. /Showing position of concrete pedestal blocks of the / proposed Citizens Rapid Transit Viaduct, 57-A-2, 1908, Dimensions: 10-1/2 x 35 in. - 27 x 89 cm.; Scale: 1" = 20'; Media: Pencil, India ink, red ink, and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 4 (Folder 07)
    Drawn By: City Eng'r's Office / Fontaine Jones / Asst City Engr
  - Bridge - Plan for / Proposed Bridge over Bacon Quarter Branch / at Oak Street, 18-D-1, 1908, Dimensions: 21-1/2 x 31-3/4 in. - 54 x 81 cm.; Scale: 1/2" = 1'; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 08)
    Drawn By: City Eng'r's Office / Richmond, Va.
  - Bridge - Richmond, Va. / Proposed Trestle Filling and Changes in Trestle Bents on Main line at 16th St. / Between Marshall and Clay Streets., 42-A-5, 1909, Dimensions: 14 x 16-3/4 in. -36 x 43 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: Blueprint with red ink notations (damaged); Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
    Drawn By: Division Engineers Office - Richmond, Va.
  - Bridge - Plan Showing / Proposed Location of New Bridge / Across / James River, 65-A-2c, 1910, Dimensions: 31 x 73 in. - 79 x cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil, India ink, and colored inks on linen; Sheets: 3 (Folder 06)
    Drawn By: Office of City Engineer / Richmond, Va. / E.J. Keegan / Ass't. Engineer
  - Bridge - Mayo [Free] Bridge/Concrete Steel Arches Across the James River/14th St., Mayo's Island, Hull St./Richmond, Virginia, Y-9786, 1911, Dimensions: Various; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprints; Sheets: 11 (Folder Roll 6)
    Drawn By: I. J. Smith & Company, Engineers and Contractors, Richmond, Va./Concrete Steel Engineering Co., Consulting Engineers, Park Row Bldg., New York, NY
  - Bridge - Ninth St. Bridge / Reinforced Concrete Arches and Approaches / Over James River, 10808a-D-4, 1913, Dimensions: 18 x 144 in. - 46 x 365 cm.; Scale: None; Media: Brownline print on paper (heavily damaged; in several fragments); Sheets: 1 (Folder 11)
    Drawn By: Designed and Drawn by L. L. Bass, J. N. Eubank & Sos. S. Pe
  - Bridge - Plan / Showing Proposed Construction in Hull Street Approach to Mayo Bridge / Adjoining Building of Standard Paper Mfg. Co., 61-C-2, 1913, Dimensions: 19-1/4 x 36-1/2 in. - 49 x 93 cm.; Scale: 1" = 10'; Media: India ink and red ink on linen graph paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 06)
    Drawn By: Office of Resident Engineer, Mayo Bridge. / Chas E. Bolling, City Engineer
  - Bridge - Reinforced Concrete Bridge / Over the / Dock / at / 17th Street, 67-C-2, 1914, Dimensions: 28 x 44 in. - 71 x 112 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder 07)
    Drawn By: City Engineer's Office, Richmond, Va
  - Bridge - City of Richmond, Va. / Timber Footwalk Across the Dock / at 17th St., 74-C-2, 1914, Dimensions: 15-1/4 x 33 in. - 39 x 84 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
  - Bridge - Timber Bridge over Southern Railway / in / Lester Street, 54-C-1, 1914, Dimensions: 28-1/4 x 42 in. - 72 x 107 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: Pencil, India ink, and red ink on heavy paper; Sheets: 1 (Folder 10)
    Drawn By: Office of City Eng'r / Richmond, Va. / G. M. Bowers / Asst. Eng'r
  - Bridge - Plan - Elevation and Details / of / Steel I Beam Bridge / over the / Dock / at / 17th St., 66-C-2, 1914, Dimensions: 28-1/4 x 47-1/4 in. - 71 x 121 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
  - Bridge - City of Richmond, Va. / Reconstruction of 9th St. Bridge, 72-C-2, 1914, Dimensions: 22-1/2 x 38 in. - 57 x 97 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Pencil and India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
  - Bridge - Watch House and Public Comfort Station / Mayo's Island / Richmond, Va., 44-A-6, 1914, Dimensions: 36-1/2 x 27-1/4 in. - 93 x 69 cm.; Scale: 1/4" = 1'; Media: India ink and blue crayon with pencil notations on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
    Drawn By: Office of City Engineer
  - Bridge - Southern Railway / Proposed Reinforced Concrete / Highway Bridge at / Seventh St. South Richmond, Va., 40-C-3, 1914, Dimensions: 24 x 36 in. - 61 x 91 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: Blueprint; Sheets: 6 (Folder 09)
    Drawn By: Office of Chief Engineer, M. W. & S. Washington, D.C.
  - Bridge - Bridge over Gillies Creek at Fulton St. / Change in Location / Plan & Profile, 70-C-2, 1914, Dimensions: 23-1/4 x 42-1/2 in. - 58 x 107 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink, pencil, and blue ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 07)
    Drawn By: Office of City Engineer / Richmond. Va.
  - Bridge - Plan of Proposed Reinforced Concrete / Viaduct over R. F. & P. Railroad Tracks on Lombardy / St. bet. Broad & Leigh Sts., 46-B-4, 1915, Dimensions: 21 x 33 in. - 53 x 84 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink and red ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 09)
  - Bridge - Richmond, Virginia / Concrete Beam Bridge / Across the Dock / at 14th Street / Cross Section & Elevation, 10563-B-1, 1915, Dimensions: 22-3/4 x 35-1/4 in. - 58 x 89 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 2 (Folder 07)
  - Bridge - Plan & Section / of / Monument Avenue / Showing the Proposed Extension of / Monument Ave. / over the / R.F.& P. Belt Line R.R., 107-C-2, 1915, Dimensions: 24 x 39-1/2 in. - 61 x 100 cm.; Scale: Various; Media: India ink on linen; Sheets: 1 (Folder 06)
  - Bridge - Map Showing Slopes of Embankment / Forest Hill Park Avenue at Reedy Creek, 103-A-2, 1915, Dimensions: 15 x 32-1/2 in. - 38 x 82 cm.; Scale: 1" = 50'; Media: India ink on linen (stained); Sheets: 1 (Folder 10)